AMONI EROT KEVIN

★ kevinamoni20@gmail.com	من Male
Kenyan 🌐 amonikevin.com 🛅 linkedin.com/in/amoni-kevin > Monitoring & Evaluation Officer	
I am a fast and enthusiastic data enthusiast with 3 years experience who enjoys synthesizing large amounts of research a	nd data ins

I am a fast and enthusiastic data enthusiast with 3 years experience who enjoys synthesizing large amounts of research and data insight into a concise and robust story for presentation to stakeholders and making organization make sense out of it and help them make informed decisions.

Education

May 2023 - Present

Aug 2018 - Mar 2023

Employment

Jan 2023 - Present

Jan 2022 - Jun 2022

Tech Skills

Data Science

ExploreAI Academy, Johannesburg

Relevant Coursework: Preparing Data (Excel and Spreadsheets), Exploratory Data
Analysis (Python, Excel, Pandas), Data visualization (Seaborn, Matplotlib,
PowerBI/Tableau), Machine Learning (Regression, Classification), NLP and
classification, AWS foundations.

Bachelors of Science in Applied Statistics with Computing.

Moi University, Eldoret

- Graduated with Second Class Upper Division Honors in the University, Did a final year
 project on Survival analysis on HIV/AIDS patients from Migori County. Used
 knowledge on descriptive statistics tests such as mean, standard deviation and others to
 accomplish the project.
- Relevant Coursework: Applied multivariate analysis, Survival models and analysis, statistical computing.

Monitoring and Evaluation Assistant

Turk Analytica, LODWAR

- Supporting the Monitoring and Evaluation team in various projects, making the company gain 30% profit in 2023 financial year.
- Designing, developing and Implementing effective M.E.A.L systems and processes that improved company quantify projects.
- Lead the team and was able to achieve 80% productivity from the department which in turn helped the company make efficient service delivery to clients.

Data Enumerator – NAWIRI

Turkana County, LODWAR

- Conducted surveys using structured questionnaires.
 Participated in pilot testing of questionnaires and other data collection instruments.
 Ensured all necessary materials (forms, tablets, recording devices) were ready and
- functional.

Ensured data consistency and resolved discrepancies.

Made necessary adjustments based on feedback from supervisors or quality control teams.

 $_{\bullet} Entered$ data from paper forms into digital databases.

Regularly updated databases to reflect new information.

Identified and corrected errors or inconsistencies in the data

Data Analysis Excel / Spreadsheets

Python for Data Analysis PowerBI

	Machine Learning / Artificial Intelligence.
M.E.A.L Framework	Data analysis
Project Management Methodologies	
English	Swahili
Ng'aturkana	
Reading	Curious with Technology
Building data visuals	Data Mining
 Building reports and dashboarding on Po 	warRI
 Data Science Relevant Coursework: Preparing Data (Excel and Spreadsheet) Exploratory Data Analysis (Python, Excel) Data visualization (Seaborn, Matplotlib) Machine Learning (Regression, Classifi) NLP and classification AWS foundations. 	s) el, Pandas) o, PowerBI/Tableau)
 Data Science Relevant Coursework: Preparing Data (Excel and Spreadsheet Exploratory Data Analysis (Python, Exc Data visualization (Seaborn, Matplotlib Machine Learning (Regression, Classifi NLP and classification 	s) el, Pandas) o, PowerBI/Tableau)
 Data Science Relevant Coursework: Preparing Data (Excel and Spreadsheet) Exploratory Data Analysis (Python, Excel) Data visualization (Seaborn, Matplotlik) Machine Learning (Regression, Classifie) NLP and classification AWS foundations. 	s) el, Pandas) o, PowerBI/Tableau) cation)
 Data Science Relevant Coursework: Preparing Data (Excel and Spreadsheet Exploratory Data Analysis (Python, Exc Data visualization (Seaborn, Matplotlit Machine Learning (Regression, Classifi NLP and classification AWS foundations. Analytical Skills	s) el, Pandas) o, PowerBI/Tableau) cation) Communication Skills.

M & E Skills

Languages

Hobbies

Certificates

Jun 2023

Aug 2023

Qualities

References